Guide to the Maurice Shapiro Environmental Health Collection, 1919-2001 UA.90.F65
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Maurice A. Shapiro Environmental Health Collection
1919-2001
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Shapiro, Maurice A.
UA.90.F65
42 Linear Feet (41 record center boxes, 2 card file boxes)
The Maurice A. Shapiro Environmental Health Collections documents the career and research interests of Maurice A. Shapiro, longtime professor at the University of Pittsburgh's Graduate School of Public Health (GSPH). Shapiro was a noted sanitary engineer and advocate of environmental health whose research interests included air and water pollution, lead poisoning, sewage treatment, and food and housing sanitation. He was also known for his involvement in large national and international projects, several of which are documented here. Also included is material related to his career at the University, including administrative and course material. This collections includes correspondence, reports, publications, pamphlets, notes, papers, and a small amount of audio and visual material.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Maurice A. Shapiro on October 28, 1999.
Previous Citation
Maurice A. Shapiro Environmental Health Collection, 1919-2001, UA.90.F65, University Archives, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Scope and Content Notes
The material in this collection primarily documents Shapiro's research interests, along with his involvement with various environmental health projects and studies. This includes material related to his involvement with the Westernport Bay Environmental Study (based in Victoria, Australia), the Ohio River Basin Energy Study, projects in Israel, the Lake Chad Basin Energy Study (surveying the African countries of Cameroon, Central African Republic, Chad, Niger, and Nigeria) and various other projects. Also included is a large amount of material related to his areas of research in environmental health, including air and water quality, lead poisoning, sewage treatment, and food and housing sanitation. The collection also includes material related to his career as a professor at the University of Pittsburgh, including information on committees he served on, the Graduate School of Public Health's accreditation process, course material, papers from students, and many of Shapiro's own publications and project summaries. The collection includes papers, notes, correspondence, pamphlets, conference proceedings, publications, reports, and a small amount audio recordings and slides.
Biography
Maurice Ansel Shapiro, called Moshe by those who knew him, was a Professor of Sanitary Engineering, Environmental Health Engineering, and Urban Affairs at the University of Pittsburgh. Born on June 4, 1917 in Denver, Colorado, Shapiro spent much of his childhood in Palestine. His father was employed as a public health physician, and his mother as a social worker. He returned to the United States for college, receiving his undergraduate degree in Biology from Johns Hopkins University in 1941, and his graduate degree in Sanitary Engineering from the University of California at Berkeley in 1949. In between receiving his two degrees, he served as a member of the United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration during World War II as part of the United States Public Health Service. It was then that he met and married his wife, Anne.
After receiving his graduate degree, Shapiro relocated to Pittsburgh to join the newly-opened Graduate School of Public Health (GSPH) in 1951 as Assistant Professor of Sanitary Engineering. He was promoted to Associate Professor in 1958, and finally to Professor of Environmental Health Engineering in 1965. In tandem with his 1965 appointment in GSPH, he became Professor of Urban Affairs at Pitt's Graduate School of Public and International Affairs (GSPIA). He retained both positions until his retirement in 1982, after which he became Professor Emeritus.
Outside of his academic achievements, Shapiro was passionate about environmental and public health, and was heavily involved in numerous projects and organizations that promoted environmental sanitation. He was a Core Team Member of the Ohio River Basin Energy Study in the 1970s, a consultant for a World Health Organization (WHO) and United Nations Development Programme (UNDP) planning project in Lagos, Nigeria, involved with numerous projects in Israel, among others. One of the projects that he was most proud of was the Western Port Bay Environmental Study in Victoria, Australia. While on sabbatical in 1973 and 1974, Shapiro served as foundation director for the study, which was aimed at protecting the region's ecology.
Shapiro was fondly remembered as a passionate professor and a devoted family member. He was a father of five. His wife, Anne, died in September 2010; he passed away shortly after on November 10, 2010, in Portland, Oregon.
Arrangement
The Maurice A. Shapiro Environmental Health Collection is arranged into six series and numerous subseries. Information about each can be found at the series level.
Series I. Correspondence
Series II. Projects
Series III. Public Health
Series IV. Research Files
Series V. University of Pittsburgh Files
Series VI. Audio and Visual Materials
Related Material
Allegheny County Air Pollution Advisory Committee Records, AIS.1992.03, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Allegheny County, Pa. Health Department, Bureau of Air Pollution Control Records, AIS. 1980.07, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Allegheny County, Pa. Health Department Lead Survey Records, AIS. 1990.14, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System Group Against Smog and Pollution (GASP) Records, AIS.1979.21, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Environmental health -- Research.; Environmental policy -- Pennsylvania; Environmental sciences -- Pennsylvania -- Allegheny County; Environmental policy -- International cooperation; Air -- Pollution; Water -- Pollution -- Pennsylvania; Pollution -- Research; Public health -- International cooperation; Public health -- Study and teaching -- Pennsylvania; Public health administration -- Pennsylvania; Faculty papers; Slides (Microscopy); Sound recordings; Correspondence; Ohio River Valley -- Environmental conditions; Lead -- Toxicology -- Research; Sanitary engineering -- Research; Refuse and refuse disposal -- Pennsylvania; Factory and trade waste -- Environmental aspects; Food handling; Israel; Environment; Environmental policy; University of Pittsburgh; University of Pittsburgh. Graduate School of Public Health -- Accreditation; University of Pittsburgh. Graduate School of Public Health -- Faculty; University of Pittsburgh -- Faculty; Shapiro, Maurice A.; American Public Health Association; Allegheny County (Pa.). Health Department
- Correspondence, 1960-2001; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  The Correspondence Series includes assorted correspondence kept by Shapiro over the course of his career. Much of the material was arranged chronologically, though some specific topics or correspondence with certain individuals were kept separate. The series is arranged first chronologically, and then alphabetically by subject. It dates from 1960 to 2001.
  - 1960-1967 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1972-1974 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1975-1980 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1980 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1986 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1987 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1991 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1992-2001 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Academic Press, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Australia, 1974-1977 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Berger, Bernard, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Broken Hill Proprietary Co., Ltd., 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Brovender, Shlomo, 1971-1981 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Canberra College of Advanced Education, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Caulfield Institute of Technology, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - City of New York, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Ellenbogen, Eric, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Environmental Health Science Center, 1964-1975 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Graduate Education in Sanitary Engineering, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Graduate School of Public Health, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Grant proposals, 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Hemeon Associates, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Low-income housing, 1969-1979 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Monash University, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Neufeld, Ron, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Neufeld, Ron, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Parkinson's in Physics Department, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Posvar, Wesley, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Project "Pacesetter", 1977 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - River studies, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - United Nations Environment Programme, 1976-1978 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - University Environmental Health and Safety Unit, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - University of Massachusetts, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Projects, 1933-2000; II.
  The Projects Series is comprised of information on certain projects that Shapiro lead or was involved in. The series contains six subseries on Israel; Lake Chad Basin Energy Study; Ohio River Basin Energy Study; Ohio River Valley Water Sanitation Commission; Smaller Projects; and Westernport Bay Environmental Study. Geographically, these projects involve the countries of Australia, Cameroon, Central African Republic, Chad, China, Israel, Niger, Nigeria, Russia, St. Lucia, and the United States of America (the states of of Illinois, Indiana, Kentucky, Maryland, New York, North Carolina, Ohio, Pennsylvania, Tennessee and West Virginia).The material in this series dates from 1933 to 2000, is arranged alphabetically, and includes notes, publications, reports, research data, and correspondence.
  - Israel, 1951-2000; 1.
    - Annual Report of the Israel Water Co., 1968 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Annual Report of the Israel Water Co. laboratory, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Department of State, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - "The Development of Israel's Water Resources", 1972 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - The Environment in Israel, 1972-1979 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - "Experiments in Treatment of Taste and Odor in the Israel National Water System", 1970 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Health Services in Israel, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Israel Environmental Bulletin, 1975-1988 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Israel Environmental Bulletin, 1989-2000 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Israel in the Mediterranean Ecosystem, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Israel Today, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Israel's National Water Carrier, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - The Jordan Project, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - National Environmental Health Research Institute, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - "Plan for Wastewater Treatment and Reuse in the Dan Region", undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Programs in Environmental Science and Technology, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Public Health, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Reports in Hebrew, 1965-1979 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - State of Israel publications lists, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Tahal, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - "Taste and Odor in the Reservoirs of the Israel National Water System", 1969 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Trip, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - U.S. Committee for the Israel Environment, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Water Pollution Control, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - World Health Organization, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Lake Chad Basin Energy Study, 1962-1980; 2.
    - Background research, 1977-1979 (Box 2, Folder 34-36)
    - Draft final report, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Field report, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Metropolitan Lagos, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Metropolitan Lagos, 1962-1980 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Notes, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Survey of the Water Resources of the Chad Basin for Development Purposes, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Ohio River Basin Energy Study, 1968-1981; 3.
    - Project Summary, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Phase 1, "Interim Findings", 1977 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Phase 1, "Development of Baseline Data for the Ohio River Basin Energy Study", 1977 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Phase 1, "Preliminary Technology Assessment Report, Part 1", 1977 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Phase 1, "Social Aspects of Power Plant Siting", 1977 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Phase 1, "Preliminary Technology Assessment Report, Part 3", 1977 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Phase 1, "A Benefit-Cost Analysis of Power in the ORBES Region", 1977 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Phase 1, "Legal Analysis of Institutional Accountability for the Ohio River Basin", 1977 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Phase 1, "Energy Transportation/Distribution in the Ohio River Basin", 1977 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Phase 1, "Issues Related to Water Allocation in the Lower Ohio River Basin", 1977 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Phase 1, "Radionuclide and Metal Ion Content of Late Summer Ohio River Sediments", 1977 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Phase 1, "Independent Comments", 1978 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Phase 2, "Air Quality and Related Impacts", 1980 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Phase 2, "Capital Requirements and Busbar Costs for Power in the Ohio River Basin, 1985 and 2000", 1980 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Phase 2, "Comments on the Ohio River Basin Energy Study", 1981 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Phase 2, "Crop and Forest Losses Due to Current and Projected Emissions from Coal-Fired Power Plants in the Ohio River Basin", 1980 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Phase 2, "An Economic Analysis of Coal Supply in the Ohio River Basin Energy Study Region", 1980 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Phase 2, "An Economic Analysis of the Electric Utility Sector in the Ohio River Basin Region", 1979 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Phase 2, "Economic Losses in the Columbus SMSA Due to Long-Range Transport of Airborne Residuals in the Ohio River Basin Energy Study Region", 1980 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Phase 2, "Energy Consumption in the Ohio River Basin Energy Study Region, 1974, by End User and Fuel Type", 1979 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Phase 2, "Energy Facility Siting Procedures, Criteria, and Public Participation in the Ohio River Basin Energy Study Region", 1980 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Phase 2, "Energy Production and Residual Heating: Taxation, Subsidies, and Comparative Costs", 1980 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Phase 2, "Environment Directorate Air Management Group: Managing the Sulfur Problem", 1979 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Phase 2, "The Future of Air Resources and Other Factors Affecting Energy Development", 1977 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Phase 2, "Health Aspects", 1980 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Phase 2, "Land Use and Terrestrial Ecology", 1980 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Phase 2, "Legal and Institutional Aspects of Interstate Power Plant Development in the Ohio River Basin Energy Study Region", 1980 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Phase 2, "Main Report", 1980 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Phase 2, "A Model of Migration in the Ohio River Basin Energy Study Region", 1980 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Phase 2, "Nuclear Energy Risks and Benefits", 1980 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Phase 2, "Ohio Basin Interstate Energy Options: Constraints of Federalism", 1980 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Phase 2, "Pennsylvania Baselines: Part 1, Sections 1-3", 1979 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Phase 2, "Pennsylvania Baselines: Part 2, Chapter 1, Sections 1-3", 1979 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Phase 2, "Pennsylvania Baselines: Part 2, Chapter 1, Section 4", 1979 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Phase 2, "Pennsylvania Baselines: Part 2, Chapter 1, Section 5", 1979 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Phase 2, "Pennsylvania Baselines: Part 2, Chapter 1, Section 6", 1979 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Phase 2, "Pennsylvania Baselines: Part 2, Chapter 1, Section 7", 1979 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Phase 2, "Pennsylvania Baselines: Part 2, Chapter 2", 1979 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Phase 2, "Regional Socioeconomic Impacts of Alternative Energy Scenarios for the Ohio River Basin Energy Study Region", 1980 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Phase 2, "Site-Specific Socioeconomic Impacts: Seven Case Studies in the Ohio River Basin Energy Study Region", 1979 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Phase 2, "Symposium on Energy and Human Health: Human Costs of Electric Power Generation", 1979 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Advisory Committee, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - "Air Quality Studies in Support of the Ohio River Basin Energy Study", 1979 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Comments, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Figures, undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - "Flue Gas Desulfurization System" working paper, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Health aspects, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - "An Integrated Technology Assessment of Electric Utility Energy Systems", 1978 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Ohio River Basin Commission, 1968-1975 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Ohio River Basin Commission, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Ohio River Basin Commission, 1976-1978 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Symposium mailing list, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Ohio River Valley Water Sanitation Commission, 1968-1996; 4.
    - Advisory Committee, 1982-1985 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Annual reports, 1968-1983 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Annual reports, 1985-1994 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Ohio River Main Stem, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Outlook., 1989-1996 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Overview, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Quality Monitor, 1978-1992 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Siting of Major Facilities, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - A Strategy for Monitoring the Impacts of Combined Sewer Overflows on the Ohio River, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Summary of 1978 Ohio River Spills, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Water Pollution Control Program Plan, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Smaller Projects, 1933-1988; 5.
    - China, 1980-1984 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Dupont Waste Site Health Study, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Environmental Mission to Novokuznetsk, 1933 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - ERDA, 1976-1978 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Pittsburgh Burn Study, 1960-1972 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Pittsburgh Burn Study, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Pittsburgh Burn Study, 1972-1981 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - St. Lucia, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 22-24)
    - St. Lucia, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - World Health Organization, 1970-1975 (Box 5, Folder 26-27)
  - Westernport Bay Environmental Study, 1974-1992; 6.
    - Environmental Protection Act, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - "Heavy Metals in Westernport Bay", 1975 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Land Activities Model, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 3-4)
    - Land Activities Model, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous, 1979-1980 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Progress Report, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Project Reports, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 8-9)
    - Report, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Report (abridged), 1975 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Trip, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - "Westernport Bay: Anatomy of an Australian Estuary", 1976 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Westernport Bay Strategy, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Westernport Bay Symposium, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Public Health, 1948-2001; III.
  The Public Health Series contains information on files that Shapiro kept that were directly related to public health concerns, primarily in Allegheny County. The series contains six subseries: Allegheny County Health Department; American Public Health Association; Conferences and Meetings; General; Illness and Disease; and Occupational Health. This series dates from 1948 to 2001, is arranged alphabetically, and contains publications, notes, reports, research data, and correspondence.
  - Allegheny County Health Department, 1965-1995; 1.
    - Allegheny County Public Health Laboratory, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Annual reports, 1986-1993 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Annual seminar information, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Bureau of Air Pollution Control, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Community Profile Series, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Comparing Risks and Setting Public Health Priorities, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Cross-Connections, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Cryptosporidium, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Feasibility Study- Clairton, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Format for sanitary survey, undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Health Effects Task Force, 1986-1990 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Injury Prevention Program in an Economically Depressed Minority Community, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Memoranda, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Miscellaneous, 1965-1987 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Miscellaneous, 1987-1990 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Present Capacity and Future Potential, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - A Proposal to Evaluate the Options Available to the Allegheny County Department of Health in Meeting the Public Health Needs of Allegheny County, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Strategic Planning Project Goals Program, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Summary of Allegheny County Health Department 1987 Program Plan (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - American Public Health Association, 1948-1970; 2.
    - Comments and questions, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Committee on Hygiene of Housing, 1953-1954 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Committee on Hygiene of Housing, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Committee on Hygiene of Housing, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Committee on Hygiene of Housing, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Committee on Hygiene of Housing, 1958-1959 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Committee on Professional Education, 1960-1970 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - An Ecologic View of Public Health, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Engineering Section Project, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Evaluation schedule, 1950-1951 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Meeting papers, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - The Sanitary Engineer in Public Health, 1952-1953 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Sanitation evaluation schedule, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Conferences and Meetings, 1949-1997; 3.
    - American College Health Association, 1961-1962 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - American Public Works Association, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - American Society of Civil Engineers, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Chicago Air Pollution Conference, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - A Community Dialogue, undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Conference on Improving the Physical Environment of the South, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Conference at Sinclair Community College, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Congress on Environmental Health, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - International Association of Milk, Food and Environmental Sanitarians, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Institute of Health Planning Executives, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - International Conference on the Interdisciplinary Aspects of the Application of Engineering Technology to the Industrialization of Developing Countries, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 20-22)
    - Inter-Regional Seminar on Development Policies and Planning in Relation to Urbanization, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Iowa Public Health Association, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Management of Controls of Heavy Metals Conference, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - National Association of Sanitarians, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - National Conference of Interstate Milk Shippers, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - New Jersey Public Health Association Conference, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - New York State Association of Milk and Food Sanitarians, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Pennsylvania Environmental Conference, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Pittsburgh's Oil Spill, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Professional Advisory Committee on Public Health Training, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Southern Regional Legislative Seminar on Current Public Health Problems, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Symposium on Food Standards, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Theodore F. Hatch Symposium on Recent Advances in Occupational Health, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 35)